<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installation reference on c3os documentation</title>
    <link>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installation reference on c3os documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 17:56:26 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.c3os.io/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Manual installation</title>
      <link>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 17:56:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/manual/</guid>
      <description>To install manually, follow the quickstart. When the QR code is prompted at the screen, you should be able to login via SSH to the box with the password c3os as c3os user.
Note, after the installation the password login is disabled, users and ssh keys to login must be configured via cloud-init.
 Installation To start the installation, run from the console:
sudo elemental install --device /dev/sda --cloud-init $CONFIG Where the config can be a cloud-init file or a URL to it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive installation</title>
      <link>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/interactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 17:56:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/interactive/</guid>
      <description>The interactive installation can be accessed from the LiveCD and guides the user into the installation process.
It generates a configuration file, which is later accessible after installation at /oem/99_custom.yaml.
From the boot menu When loading any c3os ISOs, a GRUB menu like the following will be displayed. To access the interactive installation, select the third entry (c3os (interactive install)).
Manually The interactive installer can be also started manually with c3os-agent interactive-install from the LiveCD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated installation</title>
      <link>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 17:56:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/automated/</guid>
      <description>It is possible to drive the installation automatically by configuring a specific portion of the configuration file (install). The configuration file can be supplied then in various way, by either creating an additional ISO to mount ( if a VM, or burn to USB stick if baremetal), specifying a config via URL or even create a ISO from a container image with an embedded config file, which we are going to explore here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full P2P mesh support</title>
      <link>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/p2p/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 17:56:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/p2p/</guid>
      <description>This feature is crazy and experimental!
 This section will guide on how to leverage the p2p full-mesh capabilities of c3os.
c3OS supports p2p full-mesh out of the box. That allows to seamelessly interconnect clusters and nodes from different regions into an unified overlay network, additionally, the same network is used for co-ordinating nodes automatically, allowing self-automated node bootstrap.
A hybrid network is automatically set up between all the nodes, as such there is no need to expose them over the Internet, and either expose the Kubernetes management API outside, reducing attacker&amp;rsquo;s exploiting surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry</title>
      <link>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/raspberry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 17:56:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/raspberry/</guid>
      <description>c3os supports Rasperry Pi model 3 and 4 with 64bit architecture.
You can find arm64 raspberry images in the releases page. For example https://github.com/c3os-io/c3os/releases/download/v1.21.4-35/c3os-opensuse-arm-rpi-v1.21.4-35.img.tar.xz.
Flash the image into a SD card with dd or Etcher and place your cloud-init configuration file inside the cloud-config directory ( create it if not present ) into the COS_PERSISTENT partition, for example cloud-config/cloud-init.yaml.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take over installation</title>
      <link>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/takeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 17:56:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/takeover/</guid>
      <description>c3os supports takeover installations, see also the Elemental-toolkit docs here are few summarized steps:
 From the Dedicated control panel (OVH, Hetzner, etc.), boot in rescue mode install docker and run for example:  export DEVICE=/dev/sda export IMAGE=quay.io/mudler/c3os:v1.21.4-19 # A url pointing to a valid cloud-init config file. E.g. as a gist at gists.github.com export CONFIG_FILE=... docker run --privileged -v $DEVICE:$DEVICE -ti $IMAGE cos-installer --config $CONFIG_FILE --no-cosign --no-verify --docker-image $IMAGE $DEVICE  Switch back to booting from HD and reboot  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netboot installation</title>
      <link>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/netboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 17:56:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.c3os.io/installation/netboot/</guid>
      <description> This section is a work in progress!
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
